Katherine Maack

Software Engineer

SUMMARY

My software engineering expertise is predominantly creating and improving high-throughput Java and Kotlin services. I've owned services with public-facing endpoints as well as backend services ingesting and producing data via the kafka consumer/producer model, both styles of which include services fielding throughput on the order of millions per minute. I have helped design and implement services with RESTful APIs for data retrieval, participated in the replacement of an entire system, and am in the midst of leading my team's effort to deprecate another Java service which provides access to a shared Mysql datastore via a thrift-based Java client.

My initial experience with professional software development occurred in New Relic Support, where I contributed to building a cross-platform system information gathering tooling written in Go that aids customers in self-service troubleshooting and Support Engineers in problem analysis. I also expanded Java Agent product support for Apache Solr to versions 6.5.0+ (which we released in version3.40.0).

WORK EXPERIENCE

New Relic, Portland, OR — Software Engineer II, III, IV

May 2018 - PRESENT

Consistent contributions to reducing load on shared resources, improving data delivery and accuracy guarantees, robust testing practices, process analysis and improvements, strong and consistent written communication, and successful cross-team and cross-organization partnerships

MMF Captain / tech lead for the aforementioned service deprecation: consolidated current client usages and desired improvements, created a deprecation strategy proposal, roped in sponsors, consulted architects, met with clients to discuss needs/timeline, led code walkthroughs, mapped discussions into executable, small-scoped stories

New Relic, Portland, OR — Technical Support Engineer I, II, III

SEPTEMBER 2015 - May 2018

Experience troubleshooting customer integration with our product suite, primarily the java agent. I successfully introduced processes that reduced knowledge siloing and liaised with product and expert services teams.

Oregon State University, Corvallis, OR — *Miscellaneous*

September 2010 - August 2014

IT Associate, OSU: 3 years, monitored on-campus latency; stress tested software Website Creation Workshop Leader, Chicktech: Drupal & Bootstrap Robotics Capstone Project – gamification and human/robot data capture Participant, Intel Open Source Learning Company – MeeGo (Linux distro) and OSWALD device development

2360 SE Lindenbrook Ct. Milwaukie, OR 97222 (503) 929 7949 kmaack10@gmail.com LinkedIn Github

CORE COMPETENCIES

Data streaming via kafka

Caching for high-throughput services

Data storage and retrieval (for both heavy read and heavy write systems)

Familiarity with cloud-based platforms (e.g. Pivotal Cloud Foundry, AWS EC2/S3, Heroku) and SaaS infrastructure

Designed adversarial gamedays

JVM Community of Practice co-leader (since April 2019) organize speakers, unconfs, contribute to wider Java community at New Relic

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Java, Kotlin, Golang

Technologies (used in backend service development): Kafka, Redis, Spring Boot, Docker, S3, Postgres, MySQL, Dagger, thrift/json serialization formats

Tools: Git, IntelliJ, Gradle, Jenkins, JUnit, unix/*nix command line, Wireshark, New Relic product suite

Methodologies: Kanban, Scrum, Root Cause Analysis

EDUCATION

B.S. Applied Computer Science — Oregon State University

Minor, Mathematics Graduated Winter 2015